# **RENZO SILVA**

Delray Beach, FL | P: + 5619008952 | renzoasilva@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/renzo-silva/ | github.com/rensilva5

#### **SKILLS**

#### **Technical Skills**

- Programming Languages: JavaScript | Typescript | SQL | C# | HTML | CSS
- Technologies: React | React Native | Node is | Express | MongoDB | Firebase | Git | Bash | MySql

Languages: Fluent in Spanish English; Conversational intermediate in Italian.

Certifications & Training: Online Course in React, react-native, and JavaScript

Awards: First place in a Olympic Math at State level in Colombia. Top 10 Highest GPA two years in a row in PBSC.

## **PROJECTS**

COLOMGRAM, REPO Dec 2022

- Assembled a Instagram clone app in react using hooks states, modal, and react components.
- Created and designed using css and framer-motion.

## HACKATHON-2022 | ORGANIZED BY TECH HUB IN SOUTH FLORIDA, REPO

Sep 2022

- Created an app to create issue's tickets and render pictures and location using google-maps.
- Developed it by using React as single page application, node is, and Javascript.

## EUROPE PLANNER, LIVE | REPO

Sep 2022

• Developed a web application to narrow down best destination in Europe with review section to render reviews using react components. Styled using 'mantine.dev' library and custom CSS.

# TO DO APP USING REACT, LIVE | REPO

Aug 2022

- Assembled a Todo app to track tasks. Built it using react components and deployed in firebase.
- Designed and styled using ant.design.

#### TO DO APP USING REACT-NATIVE, REPO

Jan 2023

- Assembled a Todo app in react native using typescript
- Created by implementing hook states in react and designed styles with CSS.

#### CONTACT PATIENTS LIST, REPO

Nov 2022

- Created an app that add contacts to a list an storage in firebase.
- Implemented useState in react. Designed and customized style with CSS.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## ALLTERCO-SHELLY ROBOTICS, IoT Intern (Boca Raton, FL)

Jan 2023 – Present

- Create APIs (NodeJS, Express) for IoT devices such as plugs, lamps, and relays to enable and exchange real-time data efficiently and accurately; and building full stack software (MongoDB, Express, React, NodeJS) to control devices in a local environment.
- Collaborate with a team of 6+ engineers in AGILE/SCRUM environment to optimize the front-end of CRM for IoT engineers that are managing and assessing 1000+ IoT devices; utilizing HTML/CSS/JavaScript and component libraries.
- Develop and test new and existing IoT devices and systems to ensure they meet the desired functionality and performance criteria.
- Fix bugs or issues that arise and improve the performance of these systems by optimizing the code; built with JavaScript.

# BOCACODE, Assistant / Developer intern (Boca Raton, FL)

Sep 2022 – Present

- Assisted over 15 students in improving software engineering skills in FrontEnd and BackEnd development.
- Internet project.....

# PORTOBELLO ITALIAN CUISINE, Customer Success (Jupiter, FL)

Sep 2016 – Present

- Served an average of 500 customers on a monthly basis resulting in additional monthly food and beverage revenues of \$18,000.
- Increased annual revenues by 12% each year since 2016, resulting in sustained business growth and profitability.

## PALM BEACH STATE COLLEGE, Math Tutor (Lake Worth, FL)

Aug 2019 - Mar 2020

- Tutored 400 students in areas such as calculus, algebraic methods, and statistics resulting in 80% higher test results and GPA.
- Achieved a 5% increase in the Mathematics department statistics for test results in the 5th largest out of all 28 colleges in the Florida College System, helping the college to gain state and federal funding.

### **EDUCATION**

**BOCA CODE**, Software Engineering Career Course

Boca Raton, FL (Sep 2022)

Relevant Coursework: Software Engineering, back-end and front-end development.

**PALM BEACH STATE COLLEGE,** Associate in Arts and Computer Science Pre-Major Lake Worth, FL (Aug 2017 - May 2021) Relevant Coursework: Programming in C, C++. Introduction to Programming.